VIRGINIA MCCALL

Murfreesboro Tennessee 37128

virginiaamccall@gmail.com · https://virginiamccall.github.io/

Technical multi-tasking professional specializing in SQL, Python, Excel, and Power BI. With a systematic and analytical approach to problem-solving with ability to translate data related concepts. Pursuing a mid-level data analyst position.

SKILLS

- Technical: Access, Excel, SQL, Tableau, Python, PowerPoint, PostgreSQL, Pivot tables, Excel functions, V-Lookup, H-Lookup, Pivot graphs, NumPy, Seaborn, Plotly, Pandas Matlab Oracle.
- Data Analysis: Web-scraping, data extraction, data cleanup, A/B testing, statistical analysis, risk analyst, presentation design, data visualization, Excel dashboards, Google Analytics, querying.
- Additional Skills: Project management, business strategy, report generation, customer relations, property management (Multifamily/Market/Rad2 Hud Assistance/ Section 42 Tax Credit), communication, organization, detail oriented, root cause analysis, risk management.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

HR INTERACTIVE DASHBOARD

PYTHON, SSMS, POWER BI, PERSONAL PROJECT

Using Python, I acquired the Illinois State Employee data found at data. Illinois.gov. I created a connection between python and SSMS then retrieved the data from the SQL server and created a dashboard showing the past 12 years of employment data. View the python <u>code</u> and Power Bi Dashboard.

SHOP QUERY

SQL DATA EXPLORATION, UDEMEY ASSIGNMENT

Using MySQL, I completed several queries against shop inventory data. The skills used in this project were joins and aggregation functions. View this project here.

WORK ORDER DASHBOARD

EXCEL, PERSONAL PROJECT

Using sample data from contextures I created a dashboard using power query and power pivot View this project <u>here</u>.

EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2020 – CURRENT

RURAL CARRIER ASSOCIATE, UNITED STATES POSTAL SERVICE

- Provide exemplary customer services
- Coordinate sorting and organization for parcels
- Collaborate with mail team for effective delivery

JUNE 2019-DECEMBER 2020

PROPERTY MANAGER, SHUKAL & USGAONKAR

- Coordinated the sale of property
- Negotiated cost reducing property upgrades
- Cultivated vendor relationships to maintain property

MARCH 2019-MAY 2020

LEASING / ASSISTANT PROPERTY MANAGER, 159 TINLEY LLC

- Managed 208 market-rate units
- Provided business support for the property
- Processed collections, Bank Reconciliations and Payroll
- Collected rental fees, and deposits totaling 350K monthly
- Coordinate the execution of leases at 200% during the height of pandemic

AUGUST 2016-NOVEMBER 2018

ASSISTANT PROPERTY MANAGER/ LEASING / MARKETING, ST. CLAIR VILLAGE

- Spearheaded property marketing and screening
- Maintain accounting records and executed collections
- Organized tenant files utilizing Yardi Voyager/Rent Café/Bluemoon
- Oversaw groundskeepers, maintenance, and improvements of 115 units
- Analyze bids from contractors for property provision services resulting in a 3% decrease in expenses.

EDUCATION

DECEMENR 2014 · COMMENCED

B.A. ACTUARIAL SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF NORTHERN IOWA

Undergraduate research on the mathematical modeling of SARS data using Matlab.

SEPTEMBER 2022 • NOVEMBER 2022

FULL STACK DATA ANALYST BOOTCAMP, UDEMEY

2